Paweł ADAMCZAK Backend Developer



Kraków, Poland



I'm a backend developer with almost 10 years of professional experience. I enjoy using and creating software that can be called objectively good, or as close to it as possible. I like tasks that are out of my comfort zone and the knowledge that comes with them. I believe that good practices and attention to detail are very important in general, and especially crucial in IT. I think humility and open-mindedness are two of the most important qualities a person can have.

S SKILLS

 $\hbox{Programming Languages } \quad \hbox{Python, Go} \\$

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Elasticsearch, SQLite

Frameworks Django, Django REST Framework, Flask, FastAPI, Celery, pytest

Libraries mypy, Pydantic, httpx, Click, Rich, black, Ruff, Nox, tox, pip-tools, MkDocs

Tools Docker, Docker Compose, Terraform, CloudFormation, Ansible, git

Other AWS, GitHub CI, CircleCI, nginx, dokku, OpenAPI, JSON Schema, Sentry, Bootstrap



EXPERIENCE

November 2024 August 2018

Backend Engineer, TWENTY3

Remote / London, UK

- > Integral part of the team that rewrote company's main football data ingestion pipeline, that imports and post-processes thousands of football events every day (from multiple data providers), and exposes them through an internal API.
- > Responsible for productising proof of concepts created by the Data Science team into MVPs.
- ➤ Helped with implementing best practices, such as:
 - > Developing Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery pipelines
 - > Creating Docker based development and production environments
 - > Using JSON Schema for dynamic API documentation
 - ➤ Maintaining a CloudFormation based IaaC stack
 - > Adding Python type hints
 - > Using Pydantic for validating data from all our data providers
 - Using Sentry for error and performance tracking
 - ➤ Upgrading Python and Python packages to newer versions
 - > Centralizing log digestion
- ➤ Helped create tools used by major football clubs, media and betting companies, including SkySports, Squawka, LiveScore and William Hill.

 Python | PostgreSQL | Redis | Django | Django REST Framework | Celery | Pydantic | AWS | RDS | ECS Fargate |

 CloudFormation | Circle Cl | Sentry |

July 2018 September 2017

Platform Developer, VM FARMS

Toronto, Canada

- ➤ Part of a platform engineering team that maintained:
 - > Custom-built deployment pipeline for our clients
 - > Client facing portal, that was used to configure app environments and trigger new deployments
 - ➤ All-purpose internal CLI for our operations team, that was the glue between Terraform, Ansible, Consul and Vault
- ➤ Worked directly with our in-house operations team to provide them with the tools to efficiently provision, configure and continuously support our client's infrastructure.

 Python
 PostgreSQL
 MySQL
 Django
 Click
 Terraform
 Ansible
 Consul
 Vault
 Vagrant
 AWS

August 2017 October 2016

Backend Developer, OMNI DIGITAL

Bristol, UK

1

- ➤ Helped create and maintain internal and public facing projects for clients such as NHS, UK Chamber of Shipping and SWNS.
- > Implemented a company-wide Ansible stack used for all deployments.

Python MySQL Elasticsearch Django Wagtail Ansible Digital Ocean

September 2016 September 2015

Backend Developer, SIDNET SOLUTIONS

Remote / Warsaw, Poland

- > Created and maintained:
 - > Schedoodle, an internal tool that helped track work availability of all remote employees
 - > Official Polish site for Kolbe personality tests
 - > Canola trading platform made for one of the biggest Polish oil distributors
- > Responsible for releasing and maintaining some of our open source projects on GitHub.

Python PostgreSQL Django Bootstrap Digital Ocean

September 2015 April 2015

Backend Developer, JMR TECHNOLOGIES

Warsaw, Poland

- Helped develop and release two of the company's biggest (at the time) Python projects:
 - Fully multilingual and customisable product knowledge base
- ➤ Parcel tracking status aggregator that integrated with multiple delivery companies
- ➤ Responsible for managing our production server and creating most of our provisioning automation scripts.

Python MySQL Elasticsearch Django Fabric

EDUCATION

2013 – 2016 Warsaw University of Technology

2010 – 2013 I Liceum Ogólnokształcące w Zielonej Górze



PROJECTS

PYMONZO

Modern Python API client for Monzo public API.

Fully type annotated, with explicitly defined and validated API schemas (via Pydantic), sensible defaults, easy authentication (with automatic access token refreshing) and optional Rich support for pretty printing.

Python Pydantic httpx GitHub CI MkDocs Read the Docs

MONZ

github.com/pawelad/monz ## https://monz.pawelad.dev/

Simple CLI for quickly accessing your Monzo account.

Built on top of pymonzo.

Python Click Rich GitHub CI MkDocs Read the Docs

FAKESTER

github.com/pawelad/fakester

https://fakester.pawelad.me/

Rickroll your boss friend while preserving the element of surprise.

Simple Django website that allows creating URL redirects that help fool your boss friend.

Python Django Bootstrap GitHub CI dokku

MUSIC SNAPSHOT

github.com/pawelad/music_snapshot

Save a snapshot of your day as a Spotify playlist.

CLI for saving a part of your music listening history (taken from Last.fm) and saving it as a Spotify playlist.

Python Click Rich GitHub CI

A LANGUAGES

★ INTERESTS

Polish





- traveling
- nba
- > live music
- > open source
- photography
- music making

2

- > tv series
- movies

66 REFERENCES

Michał Wojciechowski CEO, SIDNET SOLUTIONS michal@sidnet.info

Alexandre Byeon

Principal SRE, PRODIGY EDUCATION tidhilm@gmail.com

Kyle Joseph

Full Stack Developer, TWENTY3 kyle@seoplay.co.uk